<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: recipe | My Journey To Fitness]]></title>
  <link href="http://trayburn.github.com/fitness/blog/categories/recipe/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://trayburn.github.com/fitness/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-09T21:07:01-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://trayburn.github.com/fitness/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tim Rayburn]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic Texas Chili]]></title>
    <link href="http://trayburn.github.com/fitness/blog/2012/08/04/basic-texas-chili/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-04T09:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://trayburn.github.com/fitness/blog/2012/08/04/basic-texas-chili</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kate and I have settled on a schedule where I cook dinner two nights a week, and I wanted to cook up a pot of chili for one of them.  So I sat down at my handy-dandy search engine, and asked it for "Paleo Recipe Chili", and quickly found myself at <a href="http://paleozone.posterous.com/">Paleo Eats</a>.  This is a great website with lots of good recipes, amoungst them an excellent <a href="http://paleozone.posterous.com/quick-paleo-chili">Chili Recipe</a>.  This is a real chili, for those in Texas, no beans which is great for Paleo.</p>

<p>My first adventure of using this recipe proved to result in a very hot bowl, because I mixed my own chili powder from spices in my cabinet.  I used a little to much Chipotle and Cayene Pepper powder in my mix.  Still, a damned fine bowl of fresh chili.</p>

<h2>Ingredients</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 lb ground beef (grass-fed preferable)</li>
<li>1 chopped medium onion</li>
<li>2 tbsp olive oil</li>
<li>4-5 minced cloves garlic</li>
<li>1 can organic tomatoes 14.5oz (petite-diced)</li>
<li>1 chopped green bell pepper</li>
<li>3-4 tbsp chile powder</li>
<li>2 tsp dry oregano</li>
<li>1-2 tsp ground cumin</li>
<li>salt and pepper to taste</li>
</ul>


<h2>Directions</h2>

<p>Add olive oil to a pan on medium heat, brown ground beef with chopped onion and minced garlic. Then add tomatoes, bell pepper, chile powder, oregano, cumin, and salt. Then simmer the mixture for 20 mins or until the meat and green peppers are tender and the tomatoes cook into a sauce. Salt and pepper to taste. Possibly the addition of some tomato paste might be good, though I didn't have any while making this dish this week and it tasted great.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd give this recipe 4 out of 5 stars, it's damn good chili, that is quick to prepare.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
